Suraya Clemens

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

www.suraya.xyz surayaclemens@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/suraya-clemens github.com/surayaclemens

PROFILE

I see software development as a tool to combine my love of creating cool things with my responsibility to work towards a more equitable future, and seek engagements that prioritize accessibility & inclusivity along with innovation.

Outside my work in the tech sector, my background in linguistics provided me with practical experience in both logical and humanist thinking, and my academic accomplishments demonstrate that I execute top quality work. Complementing these hard skills is an extensive background in customer service, which cultivated my ability to identify and meet interpersonal needs, and form lasting positive relationships.

My colleagues know me as an excellent communicator, initiative-taker, thorough problem solver, and big fan of jokes.

SKILLS

Strong: HTML, CSS, SCSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Angular, React, Firebase, REST APIs, Node.js, Express, Git, GitHub, Figma, Jira, Agile **Moderate:** RxJs, Flutter, Dart, SQL, User Auth, OAuth, Heroku

Learning: Next.js, Redux, GraphQL

EXPERIENCE

Comprehensive list on LinkedIn

Full-stack Developer | Cedulify Inc.

AUG 2022 - Present, REMOTE/MONTREAL, QC

- Developed and maintained dynamic & responsive web application using Angular, TypeScript, SCSS, Node.js, Firebase; supported mobile development as needed using Flutter and Dart
- UX & UI design including wireframes, hi-fi mockups, copywriting
- Worked closely alongside stakeholders, designers and fellow developers to facilitate a seamless workflow from initial vision to design concepts and actionable technical specifications
- Participated in code reviews, design reviews, and discussions on architecture to ensure best practices and high quality product
- Designed and implemented RESTful APIs to facilitate data exchange
- Integrated third-party APIs such as Stripe and Meta Conversions
- Showed initiative in facilitating Agile development processes, daily stand-ups, sprint planning, and reviews
- Thrived in a fast-paced startup environment, effectively multitasking and adapting rapidly changing business conditions and priorities

Research Assistant | Sociolinguistics Lab, University of Victoria APR 2021 - APR 2022, VICTORIA, BC

- Transcribed audio files accurately and efficiently for linguistic research purposes, maintaining high level of attention to detail and ensuring integrity of data, utilizing various software
- Collaborated with other researchers to adapt to project requirements, ensure best practices, and improve overall workflow of the team through proactive communication

Web Designer & Developer | Freelance

SEP 2020 - Present, REMOTE/VANCOUVER, BC

- Design new and revamp existing marketing sites for diverse clients (E.g., gaming, construction, wellness, retail industries), creating modern, engaging, and intuitive interfaces
- Utilize web development frameworks (React, Next.js) and/or content management systems (Squarespace, Wordpress) as appropriate based on client requirements
- Migrate websites to respective domains, ensuring uninterrupted online presence
- Orchestrate projects with precision, consistently delivering high-quality sites on-time and on-budget
- Leverage client and user feedback to refine designs and ensure optimal satisfaction

EDUCATION

BrainStation | Diploma, Web Development JUL 2022, VANCOUVER, BC

University of Victoria | Bachelor of Arts, Linguistics

APR 2022, VICTORIA, BC

• GPA 4.0, Undergraduate Research Award, President's Scholarship

PROJECTS

 Morphology: Gamified learning for heritage & indigenous language revitalization (Next.js, Firebase)